{"tossups": [{"question": "Emperor Constantine VII [[the seventh]] reports that this man's father, Almos, was given a land near the Dniester called <em>Etelk\u00f6z</em> to settle by their overlords, the Khazars. This man, who led the Covenant of Blood, supposedly had his head buried in a river near the city where Attila the Hun died during a marriage ceremony. The book <em>Tactics</em> recounts how Leo the Wise incited this man's confederation to war with the Bulgarian Empire. The Magyars then conquered the Carpathian basin under the leadership of, for the point, what ruler, whose descendants ruled the Kingdom of Hungary?", "answer": "<b><u>Arpad</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "During Operation Fortitude, Patton led a \"Phantom Army\" which faked an invasion of this city and its surrounding region coinciding with the Normandy landings. Edward III supposedly ordered the wealthiest citizens of this city to surrender themselves in order to end a 14th century siege, later inspiring Auguste Rodin's sculpture <em>The Burghers of</em> [this city]. For the point, name this Northern French city in historical Picardy which was held by the English for two hundred years.", "answer": "<b><u>Calais</u></b> [[kah-LAY]] (accept <b><u>Cal\u00e9s</u></b>; accept <b><u>Pas-de-Calais</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In an attempt to remove this general, Leonidas Polk led a year-long letter-writing campaign to Jefferson Davis. At Perryville, an aide attempted to coerce this general to follow up a victory with an advance, with this general choosing to retreat to the Cumberland Gap instead. This general and the namesake of a North Carolina fort defeated Union leader William Rosecrans at Chickamauga. For the point, name this Confederate general who lost at Chattanooga, leading to his replacement by Joseph E. Johnston.", "answer": "Braxton <b><u>Bragg</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Upon seeing a withdrawal during this battle, one man said \"What? Is it possible?... the gentlemen of France fleeing?\" The River Nebel fronted one side at this battle, which was called \u201ca famous victory\u201d in a poem by Robert Southey set \u201cAfter\u201d it. The Duc de Tallard [[tah-YARD]] was defeated at this battle, after which Sarah Churchill was sent a letter by the Duke of Marlborough that asked her to \u201clet [the Queen] know her army has had a glorious victory.\" For the point, name this decisive 1704 battle during the War of the Spanish Succession.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Blenheim</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "John Merriman theorized that this song was written to bolster morale during a war with the Ottomans. Featured in an interlude at the start of Giacomo Meyerbeer\u2019s [[ZHAH-koh-moh MAI-ah-BEH-uhs]] opera <em>Les Huguenots</em> [[lehs-oo-goo-NOH]], this song was once translated into English by Thomas Carlyle. This song is included in the final movement of Felix Mendelssohn\u2019s Fifth Symphony, which celebrated the 300th anniversary of the Augsburg Confession. One theory claims that this song originated as its composer entered the Diet [[DEE-et]] of Worms [[VURMS]] in 1521. For the point, name this widely-known hymn written by Martin Luther.", "answer": "<b><u>\"A Mighty Fortress is Our God\"</u></b> (accept <em><b><u>\"Ein feste Burg ist unser Gott\"</u></b></em>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In 1875, this man succeeded William Sprague IV [[SPRAYG \"the fourth\"]] as senator of Rhode Island. In a campaign named after this man, he won a series of victories at Elizabeth City, New Bern, and other locations along the North Carolina coast. Stormy weather thwarted an effort led by this man, known as the \"Mud March,\" to capture Richmond. A type of carbine was named after this general, who suffered major defeats at the Battle of the Crater and Fredericksburg. For the point, name this Union general who replaced McClellan as commander of the Army of the Potomac after Antietam.", "answer": "Ambrose <b><u>Burnside</u></b> (or Ambrose Everett <b><u>Burnside</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man touted the Promethean project, which aimed to shatter the Tsardom of Russia in the early 20th century. During the interwar period, this politician proposed the <em>Mi\u0119dzymorze</em> [[meh-JEH-more-SHAY]], a federation of states between the Baltic and the Mediterranean meant to resist Europe's great powers. This victor at the \"Miracle of the Vistula\" made formal overtures to fellow Entente members suggesting his nation should regain control of Danzig. For the point, name this \"Father of the Second Polish Republic\" who repelled the first Soviet invasion of his country.", "answer": "J\u00f3zef <b><u>Pi\u0142sudski</u></b> (or J\u00f3zef Klemens <b><u>Pi\u0142sudski</u></b>; accept pronunciations which sound more like [[PWIH-sood-skee]] or [[PIW-sood-skee]])", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This leader\u2019s current wife Chantal is the daughter of a woman who once served as mayor of Bangou. This man formerly served as Secretary-General and prime minister under his predecessor, Ahmadou Ahidjo [[ah-HEED-joe]]. This man's signing of the Greentree Agreement with Olusegun Obasanjo put an end to a conflict between Nigeria and his country over the Bakassi Peninsula. This leader's signing of a bill allowing for an additional term led to taxi strikes in Douala. At 88, this man is the oldest non-royal head of state. For the point, name this politician who became president of Cameroon in 1982.", "answer": "Paul <b><u>Biya</u></b> (or Paul Barth\u00e9lemy <b><u>Biya</u></b>'a bi Mvondo)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This onetime assistant engineer on the gunboat USS <em>Muscoota</em> helped found the Duquesne [[doo-KANE]] Mining & Reduction Company. This businessman invented a reversible frog and \u201ccar replacer,\u201d which pre-empted his most well-known invention. This man improved upon a system that forced individuals to catwalk between cars to manually conduct one process. Oil lamps were replaced as signals for railways by this man, who competed with Thomas Edison by providing alternative current solutions. For the point, name this American inventor of the railway air brake.", "answer": "George <b><u>Westinghouse</u></b> Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Off the coast of this city is its nation's only coral island, St. Martin's, which was once part of the mainland via the Tenkaf Peninsula. This largest ship-breaking port in the world experienced anti-British violence after the revolutionary Surya Sen raided its armory in 1930, forcing his troops to retreat to the Jalalabad Hills. A conflict in this city's namesake \"Hill Tracts\" occurred after the Buddhist Chakma people agitated for autonomy from the predominantly Muslim government of Hussain Muhammad Ershad. For the point, name this Bangladeshi port on the Karnaphuli River, the second largest city after Dhaka.", "answer": "<b><u>Chittagong</u></b> (accept <b><u>Chattogram</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This man ordered raids on over 900 speakeasies in his first two days as Philadelphia\u2019s Director of Public Safety. A 44-man patrol commanded by this man was ambushed at Fort Dipitie. His experiences during the American occupation of Haiti inspired a speech in which he said \"I helped purify Nicaragua for the international banking house.\" The \u201cWar is a Racket\u201d speech was delivered by this major general, who was to be installed as dictator in an alleged industrialist coup against FDR. For the point, name this anti-war activist and highly-decorated Marine who exposed the Business Plot.", "answer": "Smedley <b><u>Butler</u></b> (or Smedley Darlington <b><u>Butler</u></b>; prompt on \u201cOld Gimlet Eye\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The short-lived periodical known as <em>The Germ</em> promoted this art movement's message, with member William Holman Hunt illustrating its first issue. Model Elizabeth Siddall caught pneumonia due to being submerged in water while modelling <em>Ophelia</em>, a piece in this movement, leading to John Everett Millais [[me-LAY]] paying all her medical bills under threat of legal action. For the point, name this 19th century British art movement which aimed to return to a style prior to a namesake painter who created <em>The School of</em> <em>Athens</em>.", "answer": "<b><u>Pre-Raphaelite</u></b> Brotherhood (or the <b><u>Pre-Raphaelite</u></b>s)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Sushun and Zaiyuan were opposed by this figure in the Xinyou [[SHEEN-YOH]] Coup, allowing for this person's rise to power. This ruler created the New Policies, and launched the Wuxu [[WOO-SHOO]] Coup to end Guangxu's [[GWAHNG-SHOOS]] attempted Hundred Days' Reform. To guarantee the survival of an empire, this person engineered the Tongzhi [[TOHNG-ZHEE]] Restoration, making Prince Gong regent in the westernizing Self-Strengthening Movement. Li Hongzhang [[HOHNG-ZHAHNG]] developed the Beiyang [[BAY-YAHNG]] fleet for this woman. For the point, name this long ruling-Dowager Empress of the Qing [[CHING]].", "answer": "Empress Dowager <b><u>Cixi</u></b> [[SEE-SHEE]] (or Empress Dowager <b><u>T'zu-hsi</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The competing Ayyavole and Manigramam guilds associated with this state competed for trade supremacy in Song China, while its ruler Kulothunga [[koo-loh-TOON-gah]] established an embassy in the court of the Chinese Emperor. This state's ruler Rajendra I deployed his navy under officer Araiyan to raid the rival trading power, Sri Vijaya [[vee-JAH-yah]], in multiple 11th-century expeditions. The Maldives and the competing Pandya dynasty were conquered by Rajaraja I of this empire, who later built the Brihadisvara [[bree-HA-dah-SVAH-rah]] Temple. For the point, name this Tamil empire of Southern Indian and northern Sri Lanka.", "answer": "<b><u>Chola</u></b> Empire (or <b><u>Chola</u></b>ns; accept \"Dynasty\" in place of \"Empire\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Because of a difference in opinion, this man ordered his master of tea ceremonies, Sen no Rikyu, to commit ritual suicide. Originally from a peasant background, this man was promoted after the Battle of Inabayama Castle, taking the name Hashiba. At the Battle of Yamazaki, this man defeated Akechi Mitsuhide [[ah-KEH-chee mee-tsoo-HEE-deh]] to avenge his former lord, Oda Nobunaga [[noh-boo-NAH-gah]]. This general launched the Imjin War, which included two failed invasions of Korea. For the point, name this second \"Great Unifier\" of Japan.", "answer": "Toyotomi <b><u>Hideyoshi</u></b> (prompt on \"Toyotomi\"; accept Kinoshita <b><u>Tokichiro</u></b>; or <b><u>Hiyoshi</u></b>-maru); or <b><u>Hideyoshi</u></b> Hashiba)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "1962 riots caused by a successful lawsuit by this man led the sitting Attorney General, Robert F. Kennedy, to threaten to imprison Governor Ross Barnett until the unrest was quelled. White sniper James Aubrey Norvell shot this man multiple times while this man was on his one-man \"March Against Fear.\" Advice from Medgar Evers and the NAACP encouraged this man to challenge a Jim Crow-era Mississippi statute which barred him from going to a Jackson institution. For the point, name this first African-American to attend a segregated university by going to the University of Mississippi in 1962.", "answer": "James <b><u>Meredith</u></b> (or James Howard <b><u>Meredith</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A housekeeper named Malusha was the mother of this man, who was assisted in one campaign by Hakon the Powerful. The death of this man\u2019s brother Oleg at the hands of his other brother Yaropolk forced this ruler to flee to Norway. In 988, this father of Yaroslav the Wise married Anna Porphyrogenita [[por-\"fear\"-oh-JEH-nee-tah]], the sister of Basil the Bulgar Slayer, confirming an alliance with the Byzantines and formalizing this man's conversion to Christianity. For the point, name this Prince of Novgorod and first Christian ruler of the Kievan Rus.", "answer": "<b><u>Vladimir the Great</u></b> (accept <b><u> Volodim\u011br Sv\u0119toslavi\u010d</u></b>; accept <b><u>Valdamarr gamli</u></b>; accept <b><u>Saint Vladimir</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Most of this group camped at the Anacostia Flats, where their shacks were eventually burned. This group was initially ordered off government property by Attorney General William D. Mitchell. On the orders of Herbert Hoover, the U.S. Army, led by Douglas MacArthur, tear-gassed this group which was gathered in Washington, D.C. For the point, name this \u201cArmy\u201d of World War One veterans who demanded cash stipends during the lowest point of the Great Depression.", "answer": "<b><u>Bonus</u></b> Army", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man used the long-abandoned Okopy Fortress to hold out against an invading eastern neighbor. This leader's refusal to coordinate with French general Charles Fran\u00e7ois Dumouriez [[doo-moor-YEH]] led to his defeat at the Battle of Lanckorona to Russian forces under Alexander Suvorov. With Michael Kovats, this Eastern European nobleman reformed the American cavalry during the Revolutionary War. For the point, name this Polish noble, a leader of the Bar Confederation who died fighting for American independence.", "answer": "Casimir <b><u>Pulaski</u></b> (or Kazimierz Micha\u0142 W\u0142adys\u0142aw Wiktor <b><u>Pu\u0142aski</u></b>; accept pronunciation of \"Pulaski\" as \"Puwaski\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Henry Cabot Lodge sent Cable 243, a message to this president, which requested he sack his brother Nhu from power under the threat of an officers' coup. To protest this man's anti-Buddhist measures, monk Th\u00edch Qu\u1ea3ng \u0110\u1ee9c lit himself ablaze near the Reunification Palace. This man overthrew the last Emperor Bao Dai [[BAO-\"DIE\"]] in a fraudulent 1955 referendum, while a 1963 coup and siege of the Gia Long Palace led to his deposition and assassination. For the point, name this U.S. ally and one-time President of South Vietnam.", "answer": "Ngo Dinh <b><u>Diem</u></b> [[NYOH-DIN-YEERM]] (accept <b><u>Ngo</u></b> or <b><u>Ngo Dinh</u></b>; be very lenient on pronunciation, including accepting clearly phonetically correct pronunciations)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In this region, Bishop McQuaid found the oldest winery dedicated to producing sacramental wine for the United States' Catholic congregations. The growth of the lumber industry in this region during the 16th century occurred at \"Slab City,\" which sits on the coast of Hemlock Lake. The Commonwealth of Massachusetts purchased the western half of this region from the Iroquois following the Phelps and Gorman purchase, while the city of Ithaca, home to Cornell University, sits on this region's Cayuga Lake. For the point, name this New York region named for eleven lakes which resemble human digits.", "answer": "<b><u>Finger Lake</u></b>s (prompt on \"New York\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "Moms Mabley was one of many African-Americans who performed this genre in the Chitlin\u2019 Circuit. An influential performer of this genre likely had an affair with Marlon Brando and set himself on fire in 1980. The album <em>No Respect</em> was recorded by a performer of this genre, Rodney Dangerfield. Lenny Bruce was arrested for obscenity after a performance in this genre, as shown in <em>The Marvelous Mrs. Maisel</em>. For the point, Richard Pryor and George Carlin performed in what genre intended to make an audience laugh?", "answer": "<b><u>Stand-Up</u></b> Comedy (prompt on \"Comedy\"; accept answers indicating <b><u>Stand-up</u> </b>comedians, comediennes, or comics)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "One leader of this event, Mordechai Anielewicz [[ah-NEE-luh-vitz]], killed himself along with several supporters in their command post at the Mi\u0142a [[MEE-wah]] 18 bunker. German Chancellor Willy Brandt fell to his knees and wept at a memorial to this event while visiting an eastern neighbor. The vast majority of fighters in this conflict were deported to Treblinka in its aftermath. For the point, name this anti-Nazi \"Uprising\" in the Jewish quarter of the Polish capital in 1943.", "answer": "<b><u>Warsaw Ghetto</u></b> Uprising (do not accept or prompt on \"Warsaw Uprising\"; note to moderator: the \"Warsaw Ghetto Uprising\" occurred in 1943, the \"Warsaw Uprising\" occurred in 1944)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Bohemian chronicler Vaclav Hollar sketched an early depiction of this building while visiting its second iteration situated in Southwark [[SUH-therk]]. The land this building was on was owned by Surrey scrivener Thomas Brend, and its first production was of Ben Jonson's <em>Every Man out of His Humour</em>. Later closed by the Puritans during the Interregnum, this building first burned down due to a malfunctioning theatrical cannon during a performance of <em>Henry VIII</em>. For the point, name this London theatre, built in the late 16th century for performances of Shakespeare's plays.", "answer": "The <b><u>Globe</u></b> Theater", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "In 1867, New Jersey became the first state to outlaw this practice, doing so 104 years before the next state. The case <em>Ingraham v. Wright</em> upheld the constitutionality of this practice, which, in Mississippi and Louisiana, is prohibited on those with disabilities. The doctrine of <em>in loco parentis</em> is often used to justify this practice with alternatives like suspension. This practice often relies on the use of a wooden paddle. For the point, name this disciplinary practice used to physically punish students.", "answer": "<b><u>Corporal Punishment</u></b> in schools (accept <b><u>Spank</u></b>ing; accept <b><u>Paddling</u></b> before \u201cpaddle\u201d is mentioned; prompt on answers such as \"physical punishment\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This politician gave one of the first Romanes Lectures at Oxford with his oratory \"An Academic Sketch,\" which begins by celebrating the structure created by the Church following the fall of Rome. This so-called \"Grand Old Man\" gave a series of fiery speeches to his constituents in the Midlothian Campaign. This politician's pamphlet <em>Bulgarian Horrors</em> criticized both the Ottoman reprisal against the title minority and Benjamin Disraeli's government indifference to the matter. For the point, name this Liberal politician and four-time Prime Minister of Great Britain during the late 19th century.", "answer": "William Ewart <b><u>Gladstone</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man established a federal constabulary known as the <em>rurales</em> [[roo-RAH-les]], whose members later adopted the look of cowboys known as <em>Charros</em>. Despite his forces winning the Battle of the Puebla, this president was overthrown during the French Intervention, which placed the Habsburg Maximillian on one throne. For the point, name this first Latin American head of state of indigenous origin, a mid-19th century Mexican president from Oaxaca [[wah-HAH-kah]].", "answer": "Benito <b><u>Ju\u00e1rez</u></b> [[HWAH-ress]] (or Benito Pablo <b><u>Ju\u00e1rez</u></b> Garc\u00eda)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In this city, the tune \"Stars and Stripes Forever\" was used to signal a fire was breaking out during a performance of Barnum and Bailey's circus, resulting in the deaths of over 160 people in the 1940s. With a hundred settlers, Pastor Thomas Hooker founded this city in 1636, naming it after an English town twenty miles south of London. This site of the Mark Twain House was home to a convention which led to the downfall of the Federalist Party after talk of New England secession was leaked during the War of 1812. For the point, name this city, the capital of Connecticut.", "answer": "<b><u>Hartford</u></b> (accept <b><u>Hartford</u></b> Convention)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Prior to this event, the letter <em>In terra pax</em> was written defending the power of the Holy See and addressed directly to Leo of Ohrid. In the Kingdom of Arles, the Second Council of Lyon [[lee-OHN]] was convened at the behest of Michael VIII [[\"the eighth\"]] Palaiologos in an attempt to mend this event. In the 1960s Athenagoras I and Pope Paul VI mutually lifted excommunication on each other first levied during this historical event. For the point, name this \"Schism\" which permanently separated the Catholic and Orthodox Christian churches.", "answer": "<b><u>Great</u></b> Schism (accept Schism of <b><u>1054</u></b>; accept <b><u>East/West</u></b> Schism)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "ITT Corporation's Harold Geneen offered $1 million to defeat this man. The CIA's Track One and Track Two opposed this ruler, and even before he took office, Operation FUBELT was used against him. This Popular Unity leader was a Marxist who redistributed land, continued Eduardo Frei Montalva's liberalization of universities, and nationalized the copper industry. While besieged at the La Moneda Palace, this man committed suicide during a 1973 coup. For the point, name this Chilean socialist president who was succeeded by right-wing dictator Augusto Pinochet [[pee-noh-SHAY]].", "answer": "Salvador <b><u>Allende</u></b> [[ah-YEN-deh]] Gossens (or Salvador Guillermo <b><u>Allende</u> </b>Gossens)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The radical leftist Weatherman planned the \"Days of Rage\" in this city, causing Fred Hampton to distance the Black Panthers from them. With support from Reverend Jesse Jackson, Jane Byrne became the first female mayor of a major city after winning this municipality's 1979 election. She previously served in Richard Daly's administration of this city, which experienced Vietnam War-motivated riots during the 1968 DNC. For the point, name this Midwestern city which is the site of the former tallest skyscraper in the world, the Willis Tower.", "answer": "<b><u>Chicago</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Emile Edde [[EH-meel eh-DEH]] served as president of this country in which Galo Plaza and Odd Bull, members of the UN Group of Three, were dispatched. Robert Daniel Murphy was sent to this country during a 1958 crisis, allowing for the election of Fouad Chehab [[foo-WAHD she-HAHB]], a Maronite Christian. Dwight Eisenhower aided this country's leader, Camille Chamoun [[shah-MOON]], in Operation Blue Bat. Comprised largely of Maronites, Druze, and Muslims, for the point, what is this country in which the U.S. occupied Beirut?", "answer": "<b><u>Lebanon</u></b> (accept <b><u>Lebanese</u></b> Republic)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In one case concerning this act, Justice Samuel Alito invoked <em>Washington v</em> <em>Glucksberg</em>, holding that this act was not protected by the Due Process Clause. The movement toward legalization of this act was galvanized by the Stonewall Riots. The case <em>Loving v Virginia</em> was cited in a landmark decision that led to this act's legalization in <em>Obergefell v Hodges</em>. For the point, name this action in which two members of the same gender enter matrimony.", "answer": "<b><u>Same-sex marriage</u></b> (accept <b><u>Gay marriage</u></b>; <b><u>Homosexual marriage</u></b>; or <b><u>Lesbian</u></b> <b><u>marriage</u></b>; prompt on \"Homosexuality\"; \"Legalization of Homosexuality\"; accept answers indicating members of the LGBTQ+ community getting <b><u>married</u></b>; accept synonyms for \u201cmarriage\u201d such as \u201cmatrimony\u201d))", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This historical event coincided with the Dorian invasion, and the Luwian speaking Neo-Hittite states in Cilicia fought a prolonged series of wars during this period. The invasion of Egypt by the Sea People was partially caused by this event after the destabilization of the society of Mycenae [[my-SEE-nay]] Greek and other Eastern Mediterranean people. For the point, name this \"Collapse\" between the 14th and 12th century BCE which ushered in a \"Dark Age\" in Europe, the Middle East, and North Africa.", "answer": "Late <b><u>Bronze Age</u></b> Collapse (accept descriptions which refers to the <b><u>Bronze Age</u> </b>ending)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "In an incident in this state, \"Bootlegger Cove\" near Cook Inlet suffered landslide damage while William George Taylor of the FAA was killed in his control tower. That event, which was centered in this state, damaged the Million Dollar Bridge and later led to the deaths of twelve people in Crescent City, California. A pipeline in this state was built after Port Valdez was destroyed. For the point, name this state where the Good Friday Earthquake occurred in 1964, leveling Anchorage.", "answer": "<b><u>Alaska</u></b> (accept <b><u>Alaskaq</u></b>; accept <b><u>Anaaski</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A student from this country named Romas Kalanta set himself on fire in 1972. A reform movement known as Sajudis [[sah-YOO-dis]] advocated for the independence of this country ruled by the unicameral Seimas [[SAY-mas]] parliament. Jonas Zemaitis was a freedom fighter in this country who relied on the code-name Vytautas [[vee-TOE-tas]]. Kaunas was once the capital of this country, which was the southernmost country to form a human chain during the Singing Revolutions. For the point, what southern neighbor of Latvia was once unified with Poland?", "answer": "Republic of <b><u>Lithuania</u></b> (accept <b><u>Lietuva</u></b>; also accept <b><u>Lietuvos</u></b> Respublika)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This election year's only faithless elector was Barbara Lett-Simmons, who protested D.C.'s lack of representation. In this election year, the first Jewish candidate to be nominated for either party, Joe Lieberman, ran for vice president. Many inadvertent votes in this election year may have gone to Pat Buchanan due to the proliferation of \"butterfly ballots.\" For the point, name this election year in which Al Gore narrowly lost to George Bush by a margin of 537 votes in Florida.", "answer": "<b><u>2000</u></b> United States Presidential Election", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}